Previously on Friends:
上集回顾：
-How did the job stuff go? -He offered me one!
-工作的事怎么样？ -他给了我一份工作
You know what? This calls for a bottle of lsrael's finest!
这时候该来一瓶以色列的佳酿
The job is in Paris.
工作是在巴黎
Oh, God, please, somebody say something.
天啊, 你们说话呀
So if you take this job, you'll be moving to Paris?
如果你接受这份工作 你将要搬去巴黎吗？
Or facing a bitch of a commute.
难道是乘飞机上下班？
I know, it's huge, and it's scary and it's really far away from you guys.
我明白这很艰巨, 我感到恐惧 而且离你们那么那么的遥远
But this is such an incredible opportunity for me.
可是这对我是一个很好的机会
I've already told them about our situation with Emma..
我还跟他们说明了艾玛的情况
and they said they'll do whatever we need to make us feel comfortable.
他们答应尽力给予我方便
I mean, I'll fly back and forth, they'll fly you out. Anything we want.
我可以回来看望她, 你也可以带她去看望我  满足我们任何要求
My boss said I might be getting a new lamp in my cubicle.
我老板答应给我的睡房买一盏新的台灯
-All right. We'll work it out. -Oh, thank you. Thank you.
-好的, 没问题  -谢谢
-You sure this is what you want? -I think it is.
-这是你渴望的吗？ -我相信是
-What's going on? -I got a really incredible job offer.
-怎么了？ -我得到一份很棒的工作
-Hey, great! All right! -Good for you!
-太好了  -为你高兴
-It's in Paris. -What?
-是在巴黎  -什么？
No, no, no! No, no, no! No, too much is changing, okay?
不 不 不 发生太多改变了
First Phoebe getting married. Congratulations.
首先 菲比结婚了 恭喜
And then these two move in to a stupid house in the stupid suburbs.
然后这两个家伙要搬到 那所讨厌的房子
-Earlier, you said you'd be supportive. -It comes and goes. I wouldn't trust it!
-嘿, 今天下午你还说会支持的  -我变来变去的, 不能相信我
You guys, this is really, really important to me.
伙计们, 这对我十分十分重要
It means a lot if you could try to get onboard.
如果你们尝试接受, 我会很感激的
-Of course we can. Congratulations. -Thank you.
-我们当然会 恭喜你  -谢谢
Joey?
乔伊
No, my hugs are reserved for people staying in America!
我的拥抱只给留在美国的那些人
Joey, it would mean..
乔伊, 我
No! Get your France-going arms away from me!
不, 要去法国的人别靠近我
-Are you okay with this? -Well, it makes me feel sad, but..
-你不会难过吧  -实际上我感到伤心
-Talking to Ross. -I see.
-我是在问罗斯 -知道了
Rachel moving to another country? Not being able to see her every day?
瑞秋去了另一个国家 不能每天看到她？
How could I be okay with this?
我怎么会不难过！？
But what are we gonna do? She really needs this job.
我们又能怎么样？她需要这份工作
Do you think if Ralph Lauren offered her her old job back, she would take it?
如果拉夫.劳伦公司请她回去, 她会愿意吗？
How's that gonna happen?
这怎么可能？
Is this the best way to use one of your three magic wishes?
你就是这么使用你的3个魔法愿望的吗？
Like, I don't know, I could talk to her boss. Yeah.
也许, 我能跟她的老板谈谈
I met him at that Christmas party. I mean, we really hit it off.
对, 我跟他在圣诞派对见过面  我们相处的很好
-The guy who kept calling you "Ron"? -I didn't say we were brothers!
-是一直管你叫Ron的那个家伙吗？ -我并没有说我们是兄弟呀
Technically, this is not a hug.
技术上说, 这不算拥抱
The One Where Estelle Dies
rainystar压制iPod-MP4
You read the obituaries?
你读过讣告了?
Yeah. Well, I got a few curses on people.
是的, 而且, 我受到一些人的诅咒
I just like to see how they're coming.
我只想看看他们怎么来
-Hey, Phoebe. Hey. -Hi.
-嘿, 菲比 -嘿
The house next door to the one that we're buying just went on the market.
在我们打算买的那座房子旁边, 有一座房子也在出售
I wanna take a look at it, but Chandler doesn't.
我想去看看, 可钱德不愿意
We close escrow tomorrow.
我们明天就签约了
Seeing another house can only confuse us. We're easily confused.
再看其它房子只会迷惑自己  我们很容易感到迷惑
We're not very bright.
我们并不机灵
But what if it's better than ours? Shouldn't we look?
那如果它比我们的更好呢 至少应该看看
What do you think, Phoebe?
你怎么看, 菲比？
Well, I think that shirt makes you look like you should work at a Baskin-Robbins.
我觉得你穿这件衬衣 像雪糕餐厅的服务员
Anyway..
反正怎么都像
-Hey, isn't Joey's agent Estelle Leonard? -Yeah.
-乔伊的经理人是Estelle Lenord吗？ -对.
-She died. -You're kidding!
-她死了  -真的吗？
-That's terrible. -Yeah, last Saturday.
-真糟糕  -是的, 在上个星期
Wow! She was the first black man to fly solo across the Atlantic!
哇！她是第一个独自驾机 飞越大西洋的黑人男性
-Wait a minute, I read the wrong one. -Oh, yeah?
-哦, 等等 我看错了另一个  -哦？
-Yeah, she was just an agent. -Joey's gonna be so upset.
-她只是一个经理人  -乔伊肯定感到很难过
I know. He always wanted to be the first black man to cross the Atlantic.
是的 他一直希望成为 第一个独自驾机飞越大西洋的黑人男性
We cannot tell Joey about this.
我们不能让乔伊知道这件事
He's already flipping out about everything changing.
一切都在改变, 他都快要发疯了
This'll push him over the edge.
不能再刺激他了
-You don't think we should tell him? -Not for a while.
-你真的认为我们不应该告诉他吗？ -至少暂时不说
Let's just give him a few days to get used to everything else.
给他几天, 先消化已经发生了的事
What if he reads the paper?
如果他从报纸上看到呢？
Unless Snoopy says it to Charlie Brown, I think we're okay.
除非是八卦的史努比告诉查理布朗 否则就没问题
-May I help you? -Yeah. I'm a friend of Rachel Green's.
-有什么事吗？ -我是瑞秋格林的朋友
Actually, we met at the Christmas party about two years ago.
我们2年前在圣诞派对上见过面
-Oh, right. Don? -Close. Ron.
-哦, 是Don？ -差不多, 是Ron
Well, what can I do for you?
有什么能帮忙的吗？
Well, I'm here to see if you'll give Rachel her job back.
想了解一下, 能不能恢复瑞秋的工作？
Did she ask you to come here and do this?
是她让他来的吗？
First I have to get you to agree..
不 如果你同意了
then we'll see if she wants to come back.
我还要问问她是否愿意回来
Wow, that is tempting.
哇, 这真吸引人
She loved her job here. Let's face it, you're not gonna find anyone..
她很喜欢这份工作 实际上你找不到比她更好的人选
who did it as well as she did. Isn't that true?
是这样吗？
-She is good. -I took a shot there.
-她是很不错  -我真没料到
But I'm sorry, there's nothing I can do.
可是, 很抱歉 我无能为力
Oh, that's not true. There's nothing I want to do.
事实是, 我不想出力
I see.
好的
Thanks very much.
谢谢
-Is this your son? -Yeah, his name is Ross.
-是你儿子吗？ -对, 他叫罗斯
-What? -Nothing, it's just that it's close to Ron.
-怎么了？ -没什么, 跟Ron很接近嘛
Does little Ross like dinosaurs, by any chance?
这小小罗斯对恐龙有兴趣吗？
Yeah, they're all he talks about. Why?
是的, 他老是说起 那又怎么样？
How would he like to come with me to the Museum of Natural History..
他是否愿意和我到自然历史博物馆
after everyone else has left, just the two of us..
在其他人都离开之后, 就剩我们两个
and he can touch anything he wants?
他想摸哪里就摸哪里
I just heard it how you must have heard it, and that's not good.
我说的, 你都听到了  不是那么回事
Let me start again. I'm a paleontologist.
让我再说一遍  我是古生物学家
You'll be there with us, and the touching refers only to bones.. fossils!
你也可以在场 摸的只会是骨头和化石
-You could really arrange that? -You let Rachel come back and it's done.
-你真的可以安排到吗？ -如果你能让瑞秋回来, 那就这么定了
I guess having Rachel back wouldn't be the worst thing in the world.
我想, 让瑞秋回来, 不见得就是坏事
Yes! Thank you! This is great! Thank you so much.
太好了, 十分感谢
I swear, your kid's gonna have the time of his life.
我保证, 这是你的孩子终身难忘的经历
That's great. I worry about little Ross.
太好了 我对他挺担心的
He's always reading, collecting rocks and he's obsessed with dinosaurs.
他老是捧着书本, 收集石头  完全被恐龙给迷住了
He'll be fine!
他会正常的
-Hey, Phoebe. -Hey.
-嘿, 菲比  -嘿
-Everything okay? -I'm just mad at my agent.
-你怎么了？ -我在生我经理人的气
Estelle? Why?
Estelle？为什么？
There's a part in this TV movie that I would be perfect for..
有一部电视电影 其中的角色很合适我演...
and I didn't even get put up for it. She better have a good reason.
她没有推荐我去 她必须告诉我原因
I'm guessing she does.
我想她是有原因的
Well, I wanna hear it, because she keeps doing this.
我想听听, 她老是这样
No, wait, wait, wait! All right, I gotta go.
噢, 等等 我要先走了
Just listen. Promise me that you will wait a minute before you call her.
答应我, 等一会再打给她
Well, okay. Why?
为什么？
Because a promise between friends means never having to give a reason.
因为, 朋友之间的诺言, 从不需要有原因
I love that saying!
我喜欢这句话
-Hello? -Joey, it's Estelle.
-嗨！ -乔伊, 我是Estelle
I was just gonna call you. That's weird.
我正想打电话给你 真古怪
It's a little coincidental, but believable.
这是巧合, 但是可信
Listen, I'm sure you're wondering why I didn't get you..
我想你肯定想知道, 我为什么没有安排你...
an audition for that TV movie.
为那部电视电影试镜
Yeah, actually I am.
是的, 确实是的
I guess I dropped the ball there.
我想我失职了 哦！
That's it? You know, it seems like all you do lately is drop the ball.
就这样？我最近老是失职
Don't take that tone with me. Who do you think you are?
不要这么和我说话 你以为自己是谁？
Alan Lemon, the first black man to fly solo across the Atlantic?
阿兰 莱蒙？ 第一个独自驾机飞越大西洋的黑人男性？
No, look, all I'm saying is you're my agent..
听我说, 你是我的经理人...
and you're not getting me any auditions and I'm tired of it.
但是你没有为我争取到试镜机会  我受够了
What are you saying?
你这样说什么意思？
I'm saying that this isn't working for me anymore, okay, Estelle?
我意思是, 不能再这样了  Estelle
You're fired. Goodbye.
你被解雇了 再见
Man, tough week for Estelle.
噢, 这个星期真折磨人
-Hi. -Hi.
-嗨  -嗨
Emma left her stuffed T. rex at my house.
艾玛把这忘在我房间了
-You know she can't sleep without it. -Well, she's asleep now.
-没这她可睡不着哦  -嗯, 她现在在睡觉呢
-Stop forcing that thing on her. -Okay.
-别再塞这玩意儿给她  -好的
You're not gonna believe what happened to me today!
哦, 你绝对不会相信今天发生的事
Ralph Lauren called and gave me my job back!
拉夫.劳伦公司打电话请我回去
-No! -I mean, it was the weirdest thing.
-不会吧  -这是多么古怪呀
They fire me and then out of nowhere, they just hire me back.
他们先是解雇我 然后又无缘无故重新聘用我
I mean, that place must just be falling apart without me!
一定是没我就不行了
-So you're not going to Paris? -No, I'm still going!
-那么, 你不去巴黎了吧  -去呀 我还去
What?
什么？！
Well, when the Louis Vuitton people found out..
好吧, 当Louis Vuitton公司发现
that Ralph Lauren wanted me back, they offered me more money!
拉夫.劳伦公司请我回去 他们就提高了我的报酬
Ross, isn't that great?
罗斯, 是不是太棒了？
Hi. We're buying the house next door. Could we just take a look around?
我们有意买下旁边的那座房子  允许我们参观一下这里吗？
Sure, I'm showing it to someone else right now, but please, look around.
当然可以  我刚好带人来参观, 你们进来吧
I feel like we're cheating on our house.
我感到这是对我们房子的不忠
If we cheat, shouldn't it be with a hot, younger house..
你会为了另一座年轻漂亮的房子...
that does stuff that our house won't do?
而对老房子不忠吗？
Ours is so much better!
我们的比这里更棒
This living room is smaller, the dining room looks like a cave.
客厅更小 饭厅像个洞穴
What a hole!
真受不了
-So, what do you think? -Love it!
-你们觉得怎么样？ -喜欢!
We already have one offer. I think the lady upstairs will make another one.
我们本来有一位买家 楼上的女士是另一位
They could be our neighbors. What are they like?
是我们的邻居耶 他们是什么样的？
The woman upstairs is nice. She and her husband have two kids.
楼上这位女士很好, 她和丈夫有2个小孩
-He's on Wall Street, and she's a.. -Oh.. my.. God!
-丈夫在华尔街工作, 她是    -喔   天   呀
Sure.
没错
Hey, Joey, you wanna come with me to..?
乔伊, 你想和我去   ？
Are you okay?
你怎么啦？
Yeah, I just feel bad about firing Estelle.
我为解雇Estelle的事难过
This has gotta be killing her.
她肯定伤心死了
No, that wouldn't kill her.
她不会因此死的
A coronary embolism might.
除非她有血栓塞
I don't know. She's gotta be taking it hard. I was her only client.
她心都碎了 我是她唯一的客户
Except for this guy who eats paper.
那个会吃纸的家伙除外
And I'm guessing he eats more money than he makes.
我猜他吃的钱比挣得多
Look, I know she's not a great agent, but she did stick with me for 10 years.
我明白她不是优秀的经理人, 但我们合作10年了
-I'm gonna call her and hire her again. -No, no, no! Don't call her.
-我要给她打电话, 重新雇佣她  -不   不   不要给她打电话,
-You wait for her to call you. -Why?
-你等她给你打电话  -为什么？
Because patience is the road to understanding.
耐心是通向理解的大道
Which is the key to a happy heart.
那是得到快乐的关键
You blow me away.
你真让人吃惊, 我服了
All right, so promise you're gonna wait for her to call you?
答应我, 你等她给你打电话
-I promise. -Okay.
-我答应你  -好的
And that means never having to give a reason.
这意味着, 从不需要有原因
What a small world!
这世界真小呀
And yet I never run into Beyonce.
我还没碰到过Beyoncé(碧昂丝)
You two know each other?
你们认识？
We go way back. Before Monica made an honest man out of him..
在莫妮卡认识他之前
Chandler used to be my little love muffin.
钱德是我的小甜甜
Don't judge me.
别审我
Why not? I do.
为什么不?我要.
So are you guys thinking of getting this house too?
这么说, 你们也想要买下一座房子
Are we gonna have a bidding war? I better warn you, I'm a toughie.
如果是要投标竞价的话 我可要警告你了 我是流氓我怕谁
Don't.. Don't.. Don't..
哦, 不
Don't do that.
不要
No, actually, we are buying the house next door.
其实我打算买下隔壁那座房子
Why?
为...为什么？
I don't know why.
我不知道为什么
Oh, that decides it, then! I was on the fence.
那就这么定了  本来我还在犹豫
But knowing that you two would be our neighbors?
没想到我们会成为邻居
Now we have to get it!
那我就买下来了
Ellen, we're gonna talk numbers.
艾伦, 我们去定下价钱
This cannot be happening.
怎么会搞成这样？
The realtor said another couple made an offer.
经纪人不是说还有 另外一对夫妇有意购买吗？
Maybe the Janices won't get it! Maybe the other couple will.
珍妮丝可能就买不成了  另外的夫妇可能会买下
The only way that'll happen is if the other couple are the Hitlers!
这绝不可能发生 除非那是希特勒夫妇
Okay, okay! All right, what if we get both houses?
我们两座房子都买下来, 怎么样？
-We can turn this one into a guesthouse! -That's a great idea!
-将这里作为家庭旅馆  -真是好主意
By the way, I don't mean to sound distasteful..
不过我想知道
but when did you start crapping money?
你从什么时候开始爱乱花钱了
-You come up with an idea. -All right.
-好呀 那你来想办法  -好啊
We've still got three hours till escrow closes on our house.
还有3个小时才签约
-We can still get out. -But we love our house.
-我们现在取消还来得及  -我们喜欢这座房子
Will we love it so much with her next door?
你也同样喜欢住在她隔壁吗？
And she's gonna be louder out here too!
她还会在这大声嚷嚷,
Just the crickets and, "Oh.. my.. God!"
讨厌的"Oh.. my.. God!"
Okay. But if we don't get this house, she'll still show up wherever we go.
即使我们不买这座房子 她还是会在我们面前出现
At least if she's here, it eliminates the element of surprise.
她住在这, 起码不会再吓我们一跳
Never again will you have to hear the three words..
你不会再听到那3个字
that make your balls jump back up inside your body!
连你的蛋蛋都被吓得缩进去
Well, we have to do something. We can't have her living next door.
我们得想想办法 不能就让她住在隔壁
Oh, that does it too.
嗯, 这也会
Who is it?
谁？
It's me. Ron.
是我, Ron
Look, I know Rachel turned you down..
我知道瑞秋拒绝你了
but I think there's a way you might be able to get her to come back.
不过我有一个法子能让她会来
This may surprise you, but rehiring fired employees is not my main job.
请你别见怪, 重新聘用已经解雇的员工 不是我主要的工作
Just hear me out.
先听我说
How would you feel about offering her a raise?
给她提高薪酬, 你认为怎么样？
Not good, Ron.
不好 Ron
Perhaps I can persuade you.
可能我会说服你
What if you could give your son..
你希望送给你儿子
this genuine pterodactyl egg replica.
这么一只恐龙蛋吗？
Wow! That's pretty cool.
哇, 这很不错呀
So? Do we have a deal?
这么说   我们成交了？
-Okay, you got it. -Yes! Yes!
-好的 你成功了  -太好了！
This is gonna make me very popular.
这会让我很受欢迎
Believe me, the ladies, they love it.
喔, 相信我, 女士都喜欢它
I meant with my son.
我指的是我儿子
Good, because the ladies, not so much.
对 女士对它不感兴趣
Joey, this is Al Zebooker, the guy who eats paper.
乔伊, 我是Al Zebooker, 那个吃纸的人
I'm sure you've heard that Estelle passed away.
相信你听说了Estelle过世的消息
I wanted to let you know there 's a memorial for her..
我通知你参加追悼会
at the Westside Chapel tomorrow at 10.
在westside教堂, 明天10点
Hope you can make it.
希望你能来
Oh, my God.
天呀
-Hello? -Joey, it' s Estelle.
-你好? -乔伊, 我是Estelle
Estelle?
Yeah, I wanted to call and tell you that there's no hard feelings for firing me.
我打电话是要告诉你 我没有因为你解雇我而感到伤心
Okay. I just.. I can't believe you're calling me.
好的 真难以置信你会打电话给我
I didn't think I should just drop by.
我觉得我不应该贸然造访
No, no! Don't drop by! Don't drop by!
不, 不要来访
Anyway, you did what you had to do. I'm okay.
总之, 你继续做你的事 我很好
Can I ask you something?
能问你个问题吗？
What's it like there?
你那边怎么样？
It's all right.
还凑合
Look, kiddo, I gotta go.
我要挂了 祝你好运
Good luck with the career. You're gonna be huge!
你会飞黄腾达的
Thanks for everything, Estelle. Bye.
谢谢你Estelle 再见
"Out of area." Boy, I'll say!
不在服务区？！噢
Well, I just talked to Sid.
我们讨论过了
We are definitely putting in an offer on the house.
我们要买下这座房子
And I'll bet we get it!
一定会成功的
The Hitlers will be so disappointed.
希特勒夫妇肯定会很失望
All right, I gotta run. Tell Monica I say goodbye.
我要先走了 帮我跟莫妮卡说再见
I'll see you later, neighbor.
我们回头见, 邻居
Wait!
等等
I just want you to know that I'm so happy you're going to be here.
我想告诉你  你住在这里我很开心
Oh, me too!
噢, 我也是
Because..
因为这样
that way..
这样…
we can pick up where we left off.
我们就能再续前缘
I never stopped loving you.
我一直都爱着你
-Oh.. my.. -Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
-喔   天    -好的, 好的, 好的
I want you.
我想你
I need you.
我爱你
I must have you, Janice Litman-Goralnik nee Hosenstein.
我要你, Janice Litman-Gorelnik ne Hosenstein (犹太人姓名)
Chandler, what are you talking about?
钱德, 你在说什么啊？
Now that you live next door, we can be together every day.
你现在住在隔壁, 我们会每天在一起
Sid and Monica never have to know a thing.
莫妮卡根本不会察觉
I don't know what to say.
我不知道该说什么
I mean, you know, obviously we have this heat between us.
很显然, 我们之间还有热情
Obviously.
很显然
But I love my husband.
但我爱我的丈夫
And I know you love your wife.
我也知道你爱你的妻子
I don't think we should get this house now.
我现在认为我不应该买这座房子
Don't say that. Don't dangle the dream and take it away.
别这么说, 别打破我们的美梦
Chandler, one of us has got to be strong.
钱德 我们其中必须有一个人立场要坚定
I understand.
我知道
Although..
尽管...
Maybe just one last moment of weakness.
最后就软弱一次吧
Goodbye, Chandler Bing.
再见了, 钱德宾
They're never coming down now!
不会再出现啦
-Hi. -Hi!
-嘿  -嘿
You are never going to believe what happened to me today.
嘿, 你肯定不会相信今天的事
What?
是什么？
Ralph Lauren called, again, and they offered me more money.
拉夫.劳伦公司又打电话来了  而且他们给我更高的报酬
-They did? -Yes! It was the weirdest thing.
-真的吗？ -是的
Zelner called me and said, "We will do anything we can to get you back."
真的太古怪了  他们说愿意以任何代价请我回去
And that I should thank some "Ron."
还说我应该为此感谢Ron
I don't even know what department that guy's in!
可我连他是谁都不知道
-So, what are you gonna do? -Well, I took it!
-那么, 你决定要怎么做？ -我接受了
That's great! So you're staying in New York!
这太好了 你会留在纽约
-You're excited, right? -You know.. Look, the money's great.
-你高兴吗？ -是的 报酬很优厚
-It's certainly the easier choice. -Right.
-是理所当然的选择  -对呀
But, you know, I mean, was I looking forward to going to Paris? Sure.
我本来是盼望着去巴黎的
Was I excited about working in the fashion capital of the world?
为能在世界时装之都工作而感到兴奋
Oh, absolutely.
哦, 太棒了
Yeah, but you know, this is..
不过
It's fine. I'm fine going back to a job where I've pretty much..
这样也不错 重新回到原来的工作
gotten everything out of it that I possibly can.
我觉得还不错  尽管我已经忘掉它了
I had no idea..
我不知道
I had no idea you were so excited about Paris.
我不知道你为巴黎如此着迷
I mean, you said you were scared.
你说过你感到害怕
I mean, it was "good" scared, though, you know?
我想这是良性的害怕
I mean, like "when I moved to New York" scared.
当我搬来纽约时, 我感到害怕
Or "when I found out I was gonna have Emma" scared.
当我发现怀上艾玛时, 我感到害怕
But this is fine. This is gonna be good.
这很不错啦, 能行的
You should go.
你应该去
What?
什么？
It's what you want. You should go.
那是你希望做到的, 去吧
You really think so?
你真的这么认为吗？
I really do.
真的
But I already told Zelner that I would come back.
可是我已经答应了回去
I'm sure he'll understand.
我相信他会理解的
All right. All right! I'm gonna do it! I'm gonna go to Paris!
好的 我就这么定了  我要去巴黎
-Yeah. -Yeah.
-好啊 -好啊
I'm going to Paris!
好啊, 我要去巴黎
-Thank you, Ross. -Yeah, yeah.
-谢谢你, 罗斯 -是啊
Oh, I'm so happy.
我太高兴了
Then I'm happy too.
我也高兴
Thank you all for coming.
谢谢你们的到来
We're here today to pay our respects to a wonderful agent..
我们相聚在此怀念一位优秀的经理人
and a beautiful woman.
一位美丽的女性,
Inside.
内在美
As Estelle's only two clients, we would like to say a few words.
作为Estelle仅有的两位客户 我们有话要说
Dude, where's my speech?
我的讲稿上哪去了？
That is entertaining. Al Zebooker, everybody!
这么做很有趣 各位, 这是Al Zebooker